## **Michael Romero**

Software Developer

Bogotá, Colombia (GMT-5) (+57) 3212944609 <u>msromeroma@gmail.com</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelromero96/

Software Developer with three years experience with **JavaScript**, **TypeScript**, using libraries as **JQuery**, **React**, **React Native**, and **Node.JS**. I have experience working on projects with **Next.JS**, **SpringBoot**, **Shopify** ECommerce websites, and **mobile Apps** with React Native. I'm a self-sufficient person. I love working on eye-catching user interfaces and also play with the backend technologies as Nest JS with last JS/TS features.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Freelancer — July 2023 - Currently

- Development of some solutions fos national and international customers.
- Working with personal projects using Prototyping with Fima, and technologies as Next JS, NestJS, TurboRepo, React Native, Flutter and MongoDB.

**Tech Stack:** React, TypeScript, React Native, Redux Saga, React Native CLI, NestJS, TurboRepo.

#### Melt Studio, Full stack Developer — June 2022 - July 2023

- Facilitate returns of products from different retailers and e-commerce by developing a Mobile App using React Native, Firebase, and Google Cloud Platform with TypeScript.
  - Optimize by 40% android version of an app initially developed for iOS; I was in charge of adjusting the development environment in the google play store.
- Optimize by 20% backend management by implementing certain firebase schedule functions.
- Implemented features to handle data streams in heavy frontend components by making executable enhancements from the global store with redux Saga.

**Tech Stack:** React, TypeScript, React Native, Redux Saga, Expo, Material UI, Node.JS, Firebase, Sentry, Husky, GitLab, Shell.

## **Gradiweb, Frontend Developer** — December 2021 – June 2022

- Improved performance by developing and maintaining E-commerce web pages with Shopify CMS.
- Implemented reusable code by using Shopify block meta fields so that the client could create product compositions in their e-commerce, achieving great impact on the prompt needs in eCommerce sales.
- Improved by 25% the design aspect of customer eCommerce by the implementation of visual improvements in sections like redesign of mini cart, presentation of products, free shipping, searching bars and carousels with promotions.

**Tech Stack:** Vanilla JS, SASS, React, jQuery, Shopify.

#### Hewtec, Frontend Developer — December 2020 - December 2021

- Freelance and corporate Projects.
- Led a corporate project that consisted in migrating an expense software application from JavaPrimeFaces to react and springBoot technologies with Oracle databases. I was in charge of supporting the Frontend team and I participated in the development of 70% of this update

Tech Stack: React, Material UI, Bootstrap, Postgres, Next.Js, SpringBoot

#### **SKILLS**

Web: CSS, HTML, SASS, LESS, JavaScript, JQuery.

**Programming Languages:** <u>Advanced:</u> JavaScript, TypeScript, <u>Intermediate:</u> TypeScript, Python; <u>Basic:</u> Kotlin, Java, Dart.

**Frameworks Tools:** Advanced: React; Intermediate: React Native, Next JS, Node JS; Basic: Nest JS, GraphQL, Apollo, Django, SpringBoot.

Data Base: Intermediate: Firebase, MongoDB, Postgres Basic: MySQL, Oracle DB.

Tools: Asana, Git, Pivotal, Monday, AirTable, Shopify CLI, React Native CLI, Expo.

Languages: English; Native: Spanish.

# **Michael Romero**

Software Developer

Bogotá, Colombia (GMT-5) (+57) 3212944609 <u>msromeroma@gmail.com</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelromero96/

#### **EDUCATION**

**Universidad Abierta y a Distancia** – Bogotá D.C, Colombia. *Computer Engineering, 2020 - Currently.* **Sena – Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje** – Bogotá D.C, Colombia. *Mechatronics, Jan 2015.* 

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

**Udemy** – 2021 - Currently. **Platzi** – 2022 - Currently.

Python fundamentals (Universidad tecnológica de Bolívar) - 2022.

Java fundamentals (Politécnico Grancolombiano) – 2020.